My thinking at a particular stage was that
Quello che pensavo in una certa fase era che
the best thing I could do for anyone
la cosa migliore che potessi fare per tutti
was to bring them to hear from Srila Guru Maharaj.
era di portarli ad ascoltare Srila Guru Maharaj.
["We Are All Mahaprabhu's Men"]
["Siamo Tutti Uomini Di Mahaprabhu"]
I thought, "If I do that, what more can I offer them than that,
Pensavo: «Se lo faccio, cosa meglio di questo posso offrire loro,
if I can somehow arrange that, bring them in connection with him—
se posso in qualche modo organizzarlo, portarli in contatto con lui,
that'll be good for them, and I'll be there too,
sarebbe buono per loro, ed ance io sarei lì,
hearing what Guru Maharaj says and...
ascoltando ciò che dice Guru Maharaj e...
So, with great confidence and joy, and verve,
Allora, con grande fiducia, gioia ed entusiasmo,
I would bring God-brothers and God-sisters
portavo confratelli e consorelle
to the lotus feet of Srila Guru Maharaj.
ai piedi di loto di Srila Guru Maharaj.
And after bringing one such person...
E dopo aver portato una di queste persone...
Srila Gurudev, he took us all,
Srila Gurudeva, ci prese tutti,
at the end of Guru Maharaja's talk he took us all downstairs for a prasadam.
alla fine del discorso di Guru Maharaj ci portò tutti giù di sotto per il prasadam.
And then the idea was after taking the prasadam to return to Mayapur.
L'idea era di prendere prasadam e dopo tornare a Mayapur.
But at the end of the prasadam Gurudev came to me and said,
Ma alla fine del prasadam Gurudev venne da me e mi disse:
"Guru Maharaj wants to see you again."
«Guru Maharaj vuole vedervi di nuovo».
That was very unusual.
Era davvero insolito.
So we went back upstairs, like three of us, four of us,
Così tornammo di sopra, eravamo in tre o quattro,
to see Guru Maharaj.
per incontrare Guru Maharaj.
And Guru Maharaj said,
E Guru Maharaj disse:
"I was thinking your earnestness to serve Mahaprabhu is so great
«Stavo pensando che la vostra sincerità di servire Mahaprabhu è così grande
that He has personally supplied this prasadam.
che Egli ha personalmente provvisto a questo prasadam.
So I asked Govinda Maharaj to set some aside for me.
Allora ho chiesto a Govinda Maharaj di metterne un po' da parte per me.
I'm also taking that."
Anche io lo sto prendendo».
That's how Guru Maharaj was thinking.
É così che pensava Guru Maharaj.
And then the one devotee went, "Oh...", who was astonished, said,
E allora quel devoto: «Oh...»; era stupefatto, disse:
"Thank you! Thank you so much!"
«Grazie! Grazie tante!».
And Guru Maharaj was, "Thank you?"
E Guru Maharaj: «Grazie?».
He said, "'Thank you', that doesn't sit well with me.
Disse: «"Grazie", non fa per me.
Because, he said, that presupposes two parties.
Perché», disse, «Ciò presuppone due parti
And when one party... these two parties with separate interest,
E quando una parte... queste due parti con interessi separati,
when one party gets something from the other party,
quando qualcuno ottiene qualcosa dall'altra parte,
they say, 'Thank you'."
dice "grazie"».
And then he turns and in a very affectionate way he said,
E poi si gira ed in un modo molto affettuoso disse:
"We are all Mahaprabhu's men."
«Noi siamo tutti uomini di Mahaprabhu».
And I thought to myself, "He, who is so exalted,
E pensai: «Lui, che è così elevato,
when he says 'we', he is including us."
quando dice "noi", include noi».
But there are people in our group,
Ma ci sono persone del nostro gruppo,
when they say "we", it does not include him.
quando dicono "noi" non includono lui.
But he, who is so exalted, says, 'We are all Mahaprabhu's men'."
Ma lui, che è così elevato, dice: «Siamo tutti uomini di Mahaprabhu».
He is willing to include us in that.
Vuole includere anche noi.